{
  "quizInfo": {
    "Subject": "Practical Research 1",
    "Term": "First Quarter",
    "Title": "PR1 Reviewer Pro Max",
    "LastModified": "15 August 2025",
    "Authors": [
      "Alexander Oro"
    ],
    "References": [
      "Week-1",
      "Week-2",
      "Week-3",
      "Week-4",
      "Module 3 - Lesson 1.pdf",
      "Module 3 - Lesson 2.pdf",
      "Module 3 - Lesson 3.pdf"
    ]
  },
  "quizData": [
    {
      "question": "What came from the prefix 're' meaning again and 'search' meaning to look for?",
      "answer": "Research",
      "choices": [
        "Etymology",
        "Scrutiny Process",
        "Basic Research",
        "Research"
      ],
      "reference": "Defining Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is not only about the discovery of something unknown, but also coming up with a new explanation of something that is known?",
      "answer": "Research",
      "choices": [
        "Applied Research",
        "Etymology",
        "Scrutiny Process",
        "Research"
      ],
      "reference": "Defining Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a process of searching for something to solve?",
      "answer": "Research",
      "choices": [
        "Basic Research",
        "Applied Research",
        "Etymology",
        "Research"
      ],
      "reference": "Defining Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What has come up with developing appropriate solutions to improve the individual's quality of life?",
      "answer": "Research",
      "choices": [
        "Scrutiny Process",
        "Basic Research",
        "Applied Research",
        "Research"
      ],
      "reference": "Defining Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is universally a systematic and objective search for reliable knowledge?",
      "answer": "Research",
      "choices": [
        "Etymology",
        "Basic Research",
        "Applied Research",
        "Research"
      ],
      "reference": "Defining Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a verified approach to thinking and employing legalized instruments and steps to obtain a more adequate solution to a problem?",
      "answer": "Research",
      "choices": [
        "Scrutiny Process",
        "Basic Research",
        "Applied Research",
        "Research"
      ],
      "reference": "Defining Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the process of discovering new knowledge?",
      "answer": "Research",
      "choices": [
        "Etymology",
        "Basic Research",
        "Applied Research",
        "Research"
      ],
      "reference": "Defining Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is defined by the National Academy of Sciences as 'a systematic investigation designed to develop or contribute to generalizable knowledge?'",
      "answer": "Research",
      "choices": [
        "Scrutiny Process",
        "Basic Research",
        "Applied Research",
        "Research"
      ],
      "reference": "Defining Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What means the origin of a word and the historical development of its meaning?",
      "answer": "Etymology",
      "choices": [
        "Research",
        "Scrutiny Process",
        "Basic Research",
        "Etymology"
      ],
      "reference": "Types and Processes of Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What systematic process does research employ that differs it from other forms of discovering knowledge?",
      "answer": "Scrutiny Process",
      "choices": [
        "Research",
        "Etymology",
        "Applied Research",
        "Scrutiny Process"
      ],
      "reference": "Types and Processes of Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of research is a purely direct application but increases the nature of understanding about the problem?",
      "answer": "Basic Research",
      "choices": [
        "Applied Research",
        "Research",
        "Etymology",
        "Basic Research"
      ],
      "reference": "Types and Processes of Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What develops the scientific theories to be more understandable to the readers?",
      "answer": "Basic Research",
      "choices": [
        "Applied Research",
        "Scrutiny Process",
        "Research",
        "Basic Research"
      ],
      "reference": "Types and Processes of Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a type of research that needs an answer to a specific question?",
      "answer": "Applied Research",
      "choices": [
        "Basic Research",
        "Research",
        "Etymology",
        "Applied Research"
      ],
      "reference": "Types and Processes of Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What provides solutions and validation to apply to the real setting?",
      "answer": "Applied Research",
      "choices": [
        "Basic Research",
        "Scrutiny Process",
        "Research",
        "Applied Research"
      ],
      "reference": "Types and Processes of Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of research aims to create a new theory based on the gathered data?",
      "answer": "Qualitative",
      "choices": [
        "Quantitative",
        "Data Description",
        "Sample size",
        "Qualitative"
      ],
      "reference": "Objectives & Description",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of research aims to test a hypothesis or theory?",
      "answer": "Quantitative",
      "choices": [
        "Qualitative",
        "Data Description",
        "Sample size",
        "Quantitative"
      ],
      "reference": "Objectives & Description",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What data description is in a natural setting, making stories out of a certain phenomenon?",
      "answer": "Qualitative",
      "choices": [
        "Quantitative",
        "Measurement setting",
        "Sample size",
        "Qualitative"
      ],
      "reference": "Objectives & Description",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What data description is a measurement setting, that performs measures out of a certain phenomenon?",
      "answer": "Quantitative",
      "choices": [
        "Qualitative",
        "Natural setting",
        "Sample size",
        "Quantitative"
      ],
      "reference": "Objectives & Description",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of research uses pictures, words, sentences, paragraphs, compositions, narrations and short stories for its data?",
      "answer": "Qualitative",
      "choices": [
        "Quantitative",
        "Statistical tools",
        "Computations",
        "Qualitative"
      ],
      "reference": "Objectives & Description",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of research uses numbers, scales, hypotheses, calculations, computations, and statistics tools?",
      "answer": "Quantitative",
      "choices": [
        "Qualitative",
        "Narrations",
        "Short stories",
        "Quantitative"
      ],
      "reference": "Objectives & Description",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of research uses a small sample size, typically 5-10 respondents, based on judgment?",
      "answer": "Qualitative",
      "choices": [
        "Quantitative",
        "Large sample",
        "Population",
        "Qualitative"
      ],
      "reference": "Sample Size & Activities",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of research uses a large sample size, typically 150-200+ respondents, representative of the population?",
      "answer": "Quantitative",
      "choices": [
        "Qualitative",
        "Small sample",
        "Judgment",
        "Quantitative"
      ],
      "reference": "Sample Size & Activities",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of research activity is inductive, starting with observations and forming a new theory at the end?",
      "answer": "Qualitative",
      "choices": [
        "Quantitative",
        "Deductive",
        "Hypothesis",
        "Qualitative"
      ],
      "reference": "Sample Size & Activities",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of research activity is deductive, starting from a hypothesis or already created theory?",
      "answer": "Quantitative",
      "choices": [
        "Qualitative",
        "Inductive",
        "Observations",
        "Quantitative"
      ],
      "reference": "Sample Size & Activities",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "In what type of research are opinions based on experience or observation with no criteria used in data discussions?",
      "answer": "Qualitative",
      "choices": [
        "Quantitative",
        "Laws",
        "Rules",
        "Qualitative"
      ],
      "reference": "Data Discussion, Analysis & Outcome",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "In what type of research are opinions based on laws, rules, or other recognized principles?",
      "answer": "Quantitative",
      "choices": [
        "Qualitative",
        "Experience",
        "Observation",
        "Quantitative"
      ],
      "reference": "Data Discussion, Analysis & Outcome",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of data analysis is subjective and influenced by personal experiences and views?",
      "answer": "Qualitative",
      "choices": [
        "Quantitative",
        "Statistical",
        "Objective",
        "Qualitative"
      ],
      "reference": "Data Discussion, Analysis & Outcome",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of data analysis is statistical and objective, employing standard criteria?",
      "answer": "Quantitative",
      "choices": [
        "Qualitative",
        "Subjective",
        "Personal experiences",
        "Quantitative"
      ],
      "reference": "Data Discussion, Analysis & Outcome",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What research outcome cultivates understanding with high validity and formulates no conclusions?",
      "answer": "Qualitative",
      "choices": [
        "Quantitative",
        "High output replicability",
        "Development endorsement",
        "Qualitative"
      ],
      "reference": "Data Discussion, Analysis & Outcome",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What research outcome endorses a development, has high output replicability, and formulates a conclusion?",
      "answer": "Quantitative",
      "choices": [
        "Qualitative",
        "High validity",
        "No conclusions",
        "Quantitative"
      ],
      "reference": "Data Discussion, Analysis & Outcome",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What characteristic of research is based on observations and experiments of theories?",
      "answer": "EMPIRICAL",
      "choices": [
        "SYSTEMATIC",
        "CONTROLLED",
        "ANALYTICAL",
        "EMPIRICAL"
      ],
      "reference": "Characteristics of Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What characteristic of research follows orderly and sequential procedures, based on valid procedures and principles?",
      "answer": "SYSTEMATIC",
      "choices": [
        "EMPIRICAL",
        "CONTROLLED",
        "ANALYTICAL",
        "SYSTEMATIC"
      ],
      "reference": "Characteristics of Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What characteristic of research keeps all variables, except those that are tested/experimented on, constant?",
      "answer": "CONTROLLED",
      "choices": [
        "EMPIRICAL",
        "SYSTEMATIC",
        "ANALYTICAL",
        "CONTROLLED"
      ],
      "reference": "Characteristics of Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What characteristic of research refers to a search for facts, answers to questions and solutions to problems?",
      "answer": "EMPLOYS HYPOTHESIS",
      "choices": [
        "OBJECTIVE",
        "ORIGINAL WORK",
        "CYCLICAL",
        "EMPLOYS HYPOTHESIS"
      ],
      "reference": "Characteristics of Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What characteristic of research shows analytical procedures in gathering the data, whether historical, descriptive, and or case study?",
      "answer": "ANALYTICAL",
      "choices": [
        "EMPIRICAL",
        "SYSTEMATIC",
        "CONTROLLED",
        "ANALYTICAL"
      ],
      "reference": "Characteristics of Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What characteristic of research is unbiased and logical?",
      "answer": "OBJECTIVE",
      "choices": [
        "EMPLOYS HYPOTHESIS",
        "ORIGINAL WORK",
        "CYCLICAL",
        "OBJECTIVE"
      ],
      "reference": "Characteristics of Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What characteristic of research ensures all findings are logically based on real-life situations?",
      "answer": "OBJECTIVE",
      "choices": [
        "EMPLOYS HYPOTHESIS",
        "ORIGINAL WORK",
        "CYCLICAL",
        "OBJECTIVE"
      ],
      "reference": "Characteristics of Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What characteristic of research requires its own examination and produces the data needed to complete the study?",
      "answer": "ORIGINAL WORK",
      "choices": [
        "EMPLOYS HYPOTHESIS",
        "OBJECTIVE",
        "CYCLICAL",
        "ORIGINAL WORK"
      ],
      "reference": "Characteristics of Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What characteristic of research starts with a problem and ends with a problem?",
      "answer": "CYCLICAL",
      "choices": [
        "EMPLOYS HYPOTHESIS",
        "OBJECTIVE",
        "ORIGINAL WORK",
        "CYCLICAL"
      ],
      "reference": "Characteristics of Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What ethical code for research means to maintain all communication and not fake data?",
      "answer": "Honesty",
      "choices": [
        "Objectivity",
        "Integrity",
        "Carefulness",
        "Honesty"
      ],
      "reference": "Ethical Codes and Policies for Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What ethical code for research means to avoid biases in experimental designs, data analysis, interpretation, and expert testimony?",
      "answer": "Objectivity",
      "choices": [
        "Honesty",
        "Integrity",
        "Carefulness",
        "Objectivity"
      ],
      "reference": "Ethical Codes and Policies for Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What ethical code for research means to keep your promises and agreements?",
      "answer": "Integrity",
      "choices": [
        "Honesty",
        "Objectivity",
        "Carefulness",
        "Integrity"
      ],
      "reference": "Ethical Codes and Policies for Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What ethical code for research means to avoid careless errors and negligence?",
      "answer": "Carefulness",
      "choices": [
        "Honesty",
        "Objectivity",
        "Integrity",
        "Carefulness"
      ],
      "reference": "Ethical Codes and Policies for Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What ethical code for research means to share data, results, ideas and tools and be open to criticism and new ideas?",
      "answer": "Openness",
      "choices": [
        "Confidentiality",
        "Responsible Publication",
        "Responsible Mentoring",
        "Openness"
      ],
      "reference": "Ethical Codes and Policies for Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What ethical code for research means to protect confidential communication?",
      "answer": "Confidentiality",
      "choices": [
        "Openness",
        "Responsible Publication",
        "Responsible Mentoring",
        "Confidentiality"
      ],
      "reference": "Ethical Codes and Policies for Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What ethical code for research means that research should have been conducted in an ethical and responsible manner?",
      "answer": "Responsible Publication",
      "choices": [
        "Openness",
        "Confidentiality",
        "Responsible Mentoring",
        "Responsible Publication"
      ],
      "reference": "Ethical Codes and Policies for Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What ethical code for research means to help educate, mentor, and advise others?",
      "answer": "Responsible Mentoring",
      "choices": [
        "Openness",
        "Confidentiality",
        "Responsible Publication",
        "Responsible Mentoring"
      ],
      "reference": "Ethical Codes and Policies for Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What ethical code for research means to treat all peers fairly?",
      "answer": "Respect Colleagues",
      "choices": [
        "Social Responsibility",
        "Non-Discrimination",
        "Legality",
        "Respect Colleagues"
      ],
      "reference": "Ethical Codes and Policies for Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What ethical code for research means to strive to promote social good and avoid social harm?",
      "answer": "Social Responsibility",
      "choices": [
        "Respect Colleagues",
        "Non-Discrimination",
        "Legality",
        "Social Responsibility"
      ],
      "reference": "Ethical Codes and Policies for Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What ethical code for research means to avoid discrimination against colleagues or students on the basis of sex, races, ethnicity, and or others?",
      "answer": "Non-Discrimination",
      "choices": [
        "Respect Colleagues",
        "Social Responsibility",
        "Legality",
        "Non-Discrimination"
      ],
      "reference": "Ethical Codes and Policies for Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What ethical code for research means to be informed and obey relevant laws and institutional and governmental policies?",
      "answer": "Legality",
      "choices": [
        "Respect Colleagues",
        "Social Responsibility",
        "Non-Discrimination",
        "Legality"
      ],
      "reference": "Ethical Codes and Policies for Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What ethical code for research means to give proper acknowledgment or credits to all researchers?",
      "answer": "Respect of Intellectual Property",
      "choices": [
        "Human Subject",
        "Legality",
        "Non-Discrimination",
        "Respect of Intellectual Property"
      ],
      "reference": "Ethical Codes and Policies for Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What ethical code for research means to minimize risks that involve human lives, dignity, and privacy?",
      "answer": "Human Subject",
      "choices": [
        "Respect of Intellectual Property",
        "Legality",
        "Non-Discrimination",
        "Human Subject"
      ],
      "reference": "Ethical Codes and Policies for Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What kind of research describes the phenomena being studied?",
      "answer": "Descriptive Research",
      "choices": [
        "Correlational Research",
        "Experimental Research",
        "Historical Research",
        "Descriptive Research"
      ],
      "reference": "Kinds of Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What kind of research considers one variable at a time and is typically the entry-level type of research in a new area of inquiry?",
      "answer": "Descriptive Research",
      "choices": [
        "Correlational Research",
        "Experimental Research",
        "Historical Research",
        "Descriptive Research"
      ],
      "reference": "Kinds of Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What kind of research typically describes what appears to be happening and what the important variables seem to be?",
      "answer": "Descriptive Research",
      "choices": [
        "Correlational Research",
        "Experimental Research",
        "Historical Research",
        "Descriptive Research"
      ],
      "reference": "Kinds of Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What kind of research analyzes the relationship between two or more variables?",
      "answer": "Correlational Research",
      "choices": [
        "Descriptive Research",
        "Experimental Research",
        "Historical Research",
        "Correlational Research"
      ],
      "reference": "Kinds of Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "In what kind of research are you testing something?",
      "answer": "Experimental Research",
      "choices": [
        "Descriptive Research",
        "Correlational Research",
        "Historical Research",
        "Experimental Research"
      ],
      "reference": "Kinds of Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What kind of research deals with cause and effect?",
      "answer": "Experimental Research",
      "choices": [
        "Descriptive Research",
        "Correlational Research",
        "Historical Research",
        "Experimental Research"
      ],
      "reference": "Kinds of Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What kind of research is employed by researchers who are interested in reporting events and/or conditions that occurred in the past?",
      "answer": "Historical Research",
      "choices": [
        "Descriptive Research",
        "Correlational Research",
        "Experimental Research",
        "Historical Research"
      ],
      "reference": "Kinds of Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What kind of research is for the purpose of establishing facts in order to arrive at conclusions concerning part events or predict future events?",
      "answer": "Historical Research",
      "choices": [
        "Descriptive Research",
        "Correlational Research",
        "Experimental Research",
        "Historical Research"
      ],
      "reference": "Kinds of Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is any organized effort to gather information about target markets or customers?",
      "answer": "Market Research",
      "choices": [
        "Feasibility Study",
        "Historical Research",
        "Experimental Research",
        "Market Research"
      ],
      "reference": "Kinds of Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What provides important information to identify and analyze customer satisfaction, market needs, market size, and competition?",
      "answer": "Market Research",
      "choices": [
        "Feasibility Study",
        "Historical Research",
        "Experimental Research",
        "Market Research"
      ],
      "reference": "Kinds of Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What allows the researchers to investigate the possible negative and positive outcomes of a project before investing too much time and money?",
      "answer": "Feasibility Study",
      "choices": [
        "Market Research",
        "Historical Research",
        "Experimental Research",
        "Feasibility Study"
      ],
      "reference": "Kinds of Research",
      "term": "First Quarter"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is similar to making a house, car, or cake which needs appropriate materials and a necessary process?",
      "answer": "Designing research",
      "choices": [
        "Grounded Theory",
        "Case Study",
        "Ethnographic",
        "Designing research"
      ],
      "reference": "Designing a Research Topic",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is an example of a research topic that can be formulated based on issues encountered inside the classroom?",
      "answer": "“Parental involvement in student achievement”",
      "choices": [
        "“Parental involvement in student achievement”",
        "“Home environment on student learning”",
        "“Community outreach programs on youth behavior”",
        "“Parental discipline styles on child Behavior”"
      ],
      "reference": "Designing a Research Topic",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is an example of a research topic about learners' attitudes and hindrances?",
      "answer": "“Stress and time management among students”",
      "choices": [
        "“School cleanliness and student health”",
        "“Stress and time management among students”",
        "“Youth participation in community development”",
        "“Home environment on student learning”"
      ],
      "reference": "Designing a Research Topic",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is an example of a research topic based on observations of problems inside the classroom?",
      "answer": "“School cleanliness and student health”",
      "choices": [
        "“Parental discipline styles on child Behavior”",
        "“Community outreach programs on youth behavior”",
        "“School cleanliness and student health”",
        "“Stress and time management among students”"
      ],
      "reference": "Designing a Research Topic",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is an example of a research topic that might bother you on a daily basis at home?",
      "answer": "“Home environment on student learning”",
      "choices": [
        "“Home environment on student learning”",
        "“Parental involvement in student achievement”",
        "“School cleanliness and student health”",
        "“Community outreach programs on youth behavior”"
      ],
      "reference": "Designing a Research Topic",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is an example of a research topic that considers things that bother you at home?",
      "answer": "“Parental discipline styles on child Behavior”",
      "choices": [
        "“Stress and time management among students”",
        "“Parental discipline styles on child Behavior”",
        "“Youth participation in community development”",
        "“Parental involvement in student achievement”"
      ],
      "reference": "Designing a Research Topic",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is an example of a research topic that can come from the usual complaints of a neighbor regarding practices in the barangay?",
      "answer": "“Community outreach programs on youth behavior”",
      "choices": [
        "“Community outreach programs on youth behavior”",
        "“Home environment on student learning”",
        "“Parental involvement in student achievement”",
        "“School cleanliness and student health”"
      ],
      "reference": "Designing a Research Topic",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is an example of a research topic based on situations in the community that need to be improved?",
      "answer": "“Youth participation in community development”",
      "choices": [
        "“Parental discipline styles on child Behavior”",
        "“Stress and time management among students”",
        "“Youth participation in community development”",
        "“Home environment on student learning”"
      ],
      "reference": "Designing a Research Topic",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "question": "What research design is appropriate for the topic “Parental involvement in student achievement”?",
      "answer": "Case Study",
      "choices": [
        "Phenomenological",
        "Grounded Theory",
        "Historical",
        "Case Study"
      ],
      "reference": "Designing a Research Topic",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "question": "What research design can be used for the topic “Stress and time management among students”?",
      "answer": "Phenomenological",
      "choices": [
        "Ethnographic",
        "Phenomenological",
        "Historical",
        "Grounded Theory"
      ],
      "reference": "Designing a Research Topic",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is another research design that can be used for the topic “Stress and time management among students”?",
      "answer": "Case Study",
      "choices": [
        "Case Study",
        "Grounded Theory",
        "Ethnographic",
        "Historical"
      ],
      "reference": "Designing a Research Topic",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "question": "What research design can be used for the topic “Youth participation in community development”?",
      "answer": "Phenomenological",
      "choices": [
        "Phenomenological",
        "Case Study",
        "Ethnographic",
        "Grounded Theory"
      ],
      "reference": "Designing a Research Topic",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 1"
    },
    {
      "question": "What guideline for choosing a topic suggests you should be interested in it because you have experienced it?",
      "answer": "Interest in the subject matter",
      "choices": [
        "Availability of information",
        "Timeliness and relevance of the topic",
        "Personal resources",
        "Interest in the subject matter"
      ],
      "reference": "Writing a Research Title",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 2"
    },
    {
      "question": "What guideline is important so that when you decide on a topic, sources of information are accessible?",
      "answer": "Availability of information",
      "choices": [
        "Availability of information",
        "Limitations on the subject",
        "Personal resources",
        "Interest in the subject matter"
      ],
      "reference": "Writing a Research Title",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 2"
    },
    {
      "question": "What must be considered to ensure a research topic is current and significant?",
      "answer": "Timeliness and relevance of the topic",
      "choices": [
        "Timeliness and relevance of the topic",
        "Personal resources",
        "Limitations on the subject",
        "Interest in the subject matter"
      ],
      "reference": "Writing a Research Title",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 2"
    },
    {
      "question": "What guideline considers if a topic is limited to what the teacher suggests?",
      "answer": "Limitations on the subject",
      "choices": [
        "Availability of information",
        "Timeliness and relevance of the topic",
        "Limitations on the subject",
        "Personal resources"
      ],
      "reference": "Writing a Research Title",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 2"
    },
    {
      "question": "What guideline requires you to consider if you can finish the research in terms of your intellectual and financial capabilities?",
      "answer": "Personal resources",
      "choices": [
        "Interest in the subject matter",
        "Personal resources",
        "Limitations on the subject",
        "Availability of information"
      ],
      "reference": "Writing a Research Title",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 2"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of topic should be avoided because it is highly opinionated?",
      "answer": "Controversial topics",
      "choices": [
        "Controversial topics",
        "Highly technical subjects",
        "Hard to investigate subjects",
        "Too broad subjects"
      ],
      "reference": "Writing a Research Title",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 2"
    },
    {
      "question": "What kind of topic should be avoided as it sparks disagreement or debate?",
      "answer": "Controversial topics",
      "choices": [
        "Highly technical subjects",
        "Controversial topics",
        "Too broad subjects",
        "Hard to investigate subjects"
      ],
      "reference": "Writing a Research Title",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 2"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of topic requires expertise and should be avoided if you don't have enough knowledge about it?",
      "answer": "Highly technical subjects",
      "choices": [
        "Too broad subjects",
        "Hard to investigate subjects",
        "Highly technical subjects",
        "Controversial topics"
      ],
      "reference": "Writing a Research Title",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 2"
    },
    {
      "question": "What subjects are made difficult by the unavailability of updated reading materials?",
      "answer": "Hard to investigate subjects",
      "choices": [
        "Highly technical subjects",
        "Too broad subjects",
        "Controversial topics",
        "Hard to investigate subjects"
      ],
      "reference": "Writing a Research Title",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 2"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the result if you deal with topics that lack focus?",
      "answer": "Too broad subjects",
      "choices": [
        "Too broad subjects",
        "Hard to investigate subjects",
        "Highly technical subjects",
        "Controversial topics"
      ],
      "reference": "Writing a Research Title",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 2"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the remedy if you lack focus because you deal with broad topics?",
      "answer": "narrow it down",
      "choices": [
        "make it controversial",
        "add personal resources",
        "make it technical",
        "narrow it down"
      ],
      "reference": "Writing a Research Title",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 2"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is considered the most important element of your research as it clearly expresses the problem to be explored?",
      "answer": "Research title",
      "choices": [
        "Research title",
        "Subject matter",
        "Respondents",
        "Time period"
      ],
      "reference": "Writing a Research Title",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 2"
    },
    {
      "question": "In formulating a research title, what contains the subject matter or topic to be investigated?",
      "answer": "What",
      "choices": [
        "Where",
        "Who",
        "When",
        "What"
      ],
      "reference": "Writing a Research Title",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 2"
    },
    {
      "question": "In formulating a research title, what contains the place or locale where the research is to be conducted?",
      "answer": "Where",
      "choices": [
        "Where",
        "What",
        "Who",
        "When"
      ],
      "reference": "Writing a Research Title",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 2"
    },
    {
      "question": "In formulating a research title, what contains the participants or respondents of the study?",
      "answer": "Who",
      "choices": [
        "What",
        "Where",
        "Who",
        "When"
      ],
      "reference": "Writing a Research Title",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 2"
    },
    {
      "question": "In formulating a research title, what contains the time period of the conduct of the study?",
      "answer": "When",
      "choices": [
        "Where",
        "What",
        "Who",
        "When"
      ],
      "reference": "Writing a Research Title",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 2"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a question that a research project sets out to answer?",
      "answer": "Writing Research Questions",
      "choices": [
        "Writing Scope and Delimitation",
        "Writing Significance of the Study",
        "Writing Research Questions",
        "Writing a Research Title"
      ],
      "reference": "Designing Research Questions and Scope",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 3"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the initial step in a research project?",
      "answer": "Writing Research Questions",
      "choices": [
        "Writing a Research Title",
        "Writing Scope and Delimitation",
        "Writing Significance of the Study",
        "Writing Research Questions"
      ],
      "reference": "Designing Research Questions and Scope",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 3"
    },
    {
      "question": "What characteristic of a research question provides enough specifics that one's audience can easily understand its purpose without needing additional explanation?",
      "answer": "Clear",
      "choices": [
        "Focused",
        "Clear",
        "Concise",
        "Complex"
      ],
      "reference": "Designing Research Questions and Scope",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 3"
    },
    {
      "question": "What characteristic of a research question means it is narrow enough that it can be answered thoroughly?",
      "answer": "Focused",
      "choices": [
        "Arguable",
        "Complex",
        "Focused",
        "Clear"
      ],
      "reference": "Designing Research Questions and Scope",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 3"
    },
    {
      "question": "What characteristic of a research question means it is expressed in the fewest possible words?",
      "answer": "Concise",
      "choices": [
        "Concise",
        "Complex",
        "Arguable",
        "Focused"
      ],
      "reference": "Designing Research Questions and Scope",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 3"
    },
    {
      "question": "What characteristic of a research question is not answerable with a simple 'yes' or 'no', but requires synthesis and analysis of ideas?",
      "answer": "Complex",
      "choices": [
        "Clear",
        "Complex",
        "Concise",
        "Arguable"
      ],
      "reference": "Designing Research Questions and Scope",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 3"
    },
    {
      "question": "What characteristic of a research question has potential answers that are open to debate rather than accepted facts?",
      "answer": "Arguable",
      "choices": [
        "Focused",
        "Clear",
        "Arguable",
        "Complex"
      ],
      "reference": "Designing Research Questions and Scope",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 3"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of research problem is the opening statement of your Statement of the Problem (S.O.P.)?",
      "answer": "General Problem",
      "choices": [
        "Specific Problem",
        "Scope",
        "Delimitation",
        "General Problem"
      ],
      "reference": "Designing Research Questions and Scope",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 3"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of research problem reflects the title of your research study?",
      "answer": "General Problem",
      "choices": [
        "General Problem",
        "Significance of the Study",
        "Specific Problem",
        "Scope"
      ],
      "reference": "Designing Research Questions and Scope",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 3"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of research problem are the questions that you want to be answered in your study?",
      "answer": "Specific Problem",
      "choices": [
        "General Problem",
        "Delimitation",
        "Specific Problem",
        "Scope"
      ],
      "reference": "Designing Research Questions and Scope",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 3"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the description of the scope of the study?",
      "answer": "Delimitation of study",
      "choices": [
        "Significance of the Study",
        "Delimitation of study",
        "General Problem",
        "Scope"
      ],
      "reference": "Designing Research Questions and Scope",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 3"
    },
    {
      "question": "What will explain why definite aspects of a subject were chosen and why others were excluded?",
      "answer": "Delimitation of study",
      "choices": [
        "Specific Problem",
        "Scope",
        "Delimitation of study",
        "General Problem"
      ],
      "reference": "Designing Research Questions and Scope",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 3"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the parameters of your study?",
      "answer": "Scope",
      "choices": [
        "Delimitation",
        "Scope",
        "Significance of the Study",
        "General Problem"
      ],
      "reference": "Designing Research Questions and Scope",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 3"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the factors not included in your research study?",
      "answer": "Delimitation",
      "choices": [
        "Scope",
        "Specific Problem",
        "General Problem",
        "Delimitation"
      ],
      "reference": "Designing Research Questions and Scope",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 3"
    },
    {
      "question": "What part of a research paper identifies the beneficiaries and the benefits that it will give when the problem is solved?",
      "answer": "Significance of the Study",
      "choices": [
        "Scope",
        "Delimitation",
        "Significance of the Study",
        "General Problem"
      ],
      "reference": "Designing Research Questions and Scope",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 3"
    }
  ]
}